Finding Aid for the Ojai Music Festival Records PASC-M.0277
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Artist Biographies and Contracts, 1940s-1980s; Series 2.
  - Lewis, Daniel, 1980-1982; Photographs, correspondence, programs (Box 50, Folder 5)
    Relating to the appointment of conductor Daniel Lewis to the 1983 Festival as Music Director.
  - Lin, Cho-Liang (Jimmy), 1992; photographs, news clippings, correspondence (Box 39, Folder 15)
    Biographical information about the Taiwanese violinist.
  - Malcolm McDowell, Nicholas McGegan, Neil Mackie, 1992-1998; photographs, biographies, correspondence (Box 38, Folder 6)
    Artist bios and information
  - Margaret Lattimore; Lotte Lehman; Ezra Laderman, 1990, 1994; photographs, biographies, news clippings (Box 50, Folder 4)
    Correspondence with mezzo-soprano Margaret Lattimore; photographs of German soprano Lotte Lehman (no dates); brochure about American composer Ezra Laderman.
  - Mark Wait, 1988-1989; press clippings and correspondence (Box 40, Folder 15)
    Background material of pianist Mark Wait, and letter from Ojai Festival confirming his interest in performing there.
  - Max '91, 1991; papers (Box 71, Folder 6)
    Correspondence between Ojai staff, Peter Maxwell Davies, and Davies' management.
  - Max Davies, 1988; photographs (Box 49, Folder 2)
    Photographs of British composer Max Davies.
  - Michael Torke; Jennifer Trost, 1988; Photographs, news clippings, correspondence (Box 40, Folder 11)
    Biographical information about American composer Michael Torke and photograph of Jennifer Trost [opera singer?]
  - Michael Zearott, 1964-1972; news clippings, correspondence (Box 40, Folder 20)
    Related to conductor Michael Zearott, who joined the Ojai Festival as Music Director in 1972.
  - Michele Zukovsky, 1983-1988; photographs, biographical sketches, news clippings (Box 40, Folder 19)
    Biographical information about the principal clarinetist of the LA Philharmonic
  - Nancy Crutcher Tunnicliffe, 1988; Photographs, news clippings, correspondence (Box 40, Folder 13)
    Regarding American bagpiper Nancy Crutcher Tunnicliffe.
  - New World Symphony/Southeast, 1994; Photographs, negatives (Box 38, Folder 13)
    Photographs of the New World Symphony Brass Quintet and percussion ensemble Southbeat
  - Ojai Artist PR, 1989; photographs, papers (Box 42, Folder 14)
    Related to 1989 season, including Pierre Boulez, Janet Ferguson, etc.
  - Ostendorf, John, 1992; photographs, biographical sketches (Box 39, Folder 16)
    Biographical information about the bass-baritone.
  - Patricia Racette; Steve Reich, 1990-1992; photographs, biographies, correspondence, contracts (Box 38, Folder 17)
    Related to Patricia Racette (soprano) and Steve Reich.
  - Paul Crossley, 1990-1993; Contracts, correspondence, press kit (Box 31, Folder 7)
    Related to British pianist Paul Crossley. Includes immigration and travel records.
  - Paul Elliott, 1984-1986; photographs, biographies, news clippings (Box 49, Folder 5)
    Information about the British tenor.
  - Paula Robison, 1993-1994; photographs, biographical sketches, news clippings, correspondence (Box 40, Folder 1)
    Related to flutist Paula Robison, performing in the 1994 Festival.
  - Performers--info sent by FY '91, 1990; correspondence (Box 40, Folder 21)
    Correspondence to and from artists not considered for the Festival.
  - Peter Sellars, 1990-1991; biography, news clippings (Box 40, Folder 6)
    Related to conductor Peter Sellars, who joined the LA Philharmonic in 1990 as creative consultant.
  - Photos used for Festival '94, 1994; negatives, photocopies of photographs (Box 42, Folder 11)
    Small selection of photocopies and negatives for '94 Festival. Pictures of Paula Robison, Thomas Hampson, etc.
  - Phyllis Bryn-Julson, 1992; photographs, news clippings, correspondence (Box 39, Folder 13)
    Biographical material for soprano Phyllis Bryn-Julson.
  - Phyllis Bryn-Julson, 1993; photographs, biographies, news clippings (Box 48, Folder 5)
    Related to soprano Phyllis Bryn-Julson.
  - Ravi Shankar, 1988; Contracts, biographical sketches, photographs (Box 40, Folder 7)
    Related to sitarist Ravi Shankar's engagement at the 1988 Ojai Festival.
  - Recording Releases, 1991; papers (Box 69, Folder 2)
    Contracts and correspondence regarding artists' permission to have their performances at Ojai recorded and broadcast.
  - Richard F. Perry, 1968-1973; photographs, biographies, correspondence, contracts (Box 38, Folder 15)
    Related to Richard Perry, manager of the Glendale Symphony. Includes bills and financial records.
  - Robert Craft, 1950-1984; photographs, programs, correspondence (Box 49, Folder 1)
    related to conductor Robert Craft, who conducted at Ojai in 1954.
    Craft was personally acquainted with Mr. and Mrs. Igor Stravinsky.
  - Roger Kellaway Festival '95, 1994-1995; photographs, biographies (Box 50, Folder 1)
    Regarding pianist Roger Kellaway.
  - Roger Norrington, 1989-1991; contracts, correspondence, biographies (Box 38, Folder 11)
    Related to Roger Norrington (conductor) and his affiliation with the Festival.
  - Roger Norrington, 1989-1991; contracts, correspondence, biographies (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Santa Barbara Choral Society, draft of biographical sketch (Box 40, Folder 5)
    Incomplete sketch of the Santa Barbara Choral Society, founded in 1948.
  - Scottish Chamber Orchestra, 1991; papers, brochures (Box 69, Folder 3)
    Information regarding the SCO's engagement at the Ojai Festival.
  - Scottish Chamber Orchestra, 1991 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    Correspondence with management of Scottish Chamber Orchestra regarding their 1991 engagement at the Festival.
  - Simmons, Calvin, 1977-1982; Photographs, news clippings, correspondence (Box 40, Folder 8)
    Related to conductor Calvin Simmons and his 1978 appointment at Ojai.
  - Solo artists, 1991; papers (Box 71, Folder 2)
    Biographies and information about solo artists, such as Charles Neidich and Sanford Sylvan.
  - SouthBeat Percussion Ensemble Family Concert, June 1994; Programs, plans, photographs (Box 40, Folder 9)
    Related to percussion family concert held in Ojai.
  - Stephen Mosko, 1989; contracts, correspondence, biographies (Box 38, Folder 10)
    Related to violinst Stephen Mosko
  - Subotnick, Morton, 1980's?; List of addresses (Box 40, Folder 10)
    Says: Confidential! Distributed to composers only.
    No dates, but one address is in West Germany, i.e., pre-1989.
  - Thomas Hampson, 1994; photographs, biographies, news clippings (Box 49, Folder 11)
    Information about American baritone Thomas Hampson.
  - Unlabeled photographs, photographs and photocopies (Box 48, Folder 7)
    Unlabeled--one photograph appears to have Boulez in it. Others unclear. Includes business card for John Moeur, editor of the Ojai Valley News.
  - Ursual Oppens; Pacific Chorale 1988, photographs, biographies, correspondence (Box 38, Folder 14)
    Related to pianist Ursula Oppens and the Pacific Chorale
  - Visa/Immigration, 1991; papers (Box 69, Folder 1)
    Applications and correspondence regarding visa/immigration issues for artists performing at Ojai.
  - Washburn, Nan, 1990; News clippings and correspondence (Box 40, Folder 14)
    Regards conductor Nan Washburn, who led the Camellia Symphony Orchestra (Sacramento) in 1990.
  - Wuorinen, Charles 1974-76, correspondence, contracts, bills (Box 40, Folder 17)
    Related to the commission of Wuorinen's Reliquary for Igor Stravinsky, premiered at the 1975 Festival.
- Business Papers, 1940s-1990s; Series 3.
  - 1991-1992 Ticket Information, papers (Box 52, Folder 8)
    Seating charts, ticket sales, information for 91-92.
  - 1992 Mailing Lists, papers (Box 43, Folder 5)
    USPS postage statements and mailing lists
  - 1992 Production Contracts, Facilities, Engineering, Contracts, correspondence, drafts (Box 39, Folder 9)
    Contracts and information related to production of 1992 Festival.
  - 1993 Festival Masters, papers (Box 30, Folder 8)
    drafts of tickets, backstage passes and other materials for 93 Festival
  - 1993 Festival Production Book, Correspondence, brochures, photocopies (Box 27, Folder 6)
    Materials for production of 1993 Festival, including mailing lists, scholarship winners, program drafts
  - 1993 Festival Production Soliciting production assistants, correspondence, contracts, drafts (Box 30, Folder 5)
    Related to solicitation of production assistants from local colleges/universities for the 1993 Festival
  - 1993 May 23rd Los Angeles preview concert (Pasadena), papers (Box 53, Folder 9)
    Mailing lists and invitation for preview concert
  - 1993 Ojai Trolley Co Contract for Advertising, papers (Box 61, Folder 1)
    Contract and information regarding Ojai Festival advertising on Ojai Trolleys
  - 1993 Santa Barbara preview concert May 25 Academy of the West, papers (Box 53, Folder 10)
    Mailing lists, invitations, planning for preview concert.
  - 1993 Sets Tickets, correspondence and drafts (Box 30, Folder 3)
    Ticket data, including reserved blocks and general admission
  - 1993 Ticketmaster (Cancelled), Correspondence, contracts (Box 30, Folder 2)
    Related to Ojai Festival ending business relationship with Ticketmaster as ticket vendor
  - 93 Festival Mailing Lists, 1993; Contracts, correspondence (Box 31, Folder 1)
    Related to selling and trading of mailing lists to sell tickets
  - Alcoholic Beverage Control--Wine selling proposal, 1992; Proposal (Box 39, Folder 2)
    Related to selling commemorative Ojai wine at the Festival.
  - Annual Meeting, 1955-1973; papers (Box 48, Folder 1)
    Attendance records and minutes from annual meetings of members of the Festival.
  - Artists & Repertoire, 1982, 1991; papers, program (Box 70, Folder 5)
    1982 Program (Stravinsky Centennial); Repertoire for artists
  - Arts Center Ancillary Concerts Festival 93, 1993; Contracts, correspondence (Box 30, Folder 9)
    related to rental of Arts Center
  - Audience Development Spring Concert Ventura City Hall, 1995; papers, invitations, correspondence (Box 33, Folder 2)
    Related to pre-season Ojai concert held at Old City Hall, City of Buenaventura
  - Auto Club of So. Calif (Ticket Agency), 1966-1972; Papers (Box 48, Folder 2)
    Correspondence relating to AAA's distribution of Ojai Festival tickets as a benefit to its members. Ticket orders from previous years.
  - Board of Directors Minutes, July 1956-June 1957; Bound papers (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Minutes of board meetings with receipt and disbursement records.
  - Brainstorming poster, Post-it poster size papers (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Ideas for women's committee handwritten on large papers
    Folded up. Not in folder.
  - Brochure letters, 1960s; Correspondence and drafts (Box 36, Folder 4)
    Planning of brochure text. Includes letter from Aaron Copland with quote from him to use in printed materials.
  - Bulk Mailing, 1993; correspondence and drafts (Box 31, Folder 9)
    Related to trading of mailing lists to sell tickets.
  - Bylaws, 1971; papers (Box 84, Folder 4)
    Bylaws of the Ojai Women's Committee as well as a letter from the IRS.
  - CAC Touring '93 Kronos Back-Up, 1993; Contracts, correspondence (Box 27, Folder 3)
    Documents related to the Kronos Quartet performing in the 1993 Ojai Festival
  - Calendar of events, 1992-1993; papers (Box 51, Folder 4)
    Correspondence and dates for events during the 1992-93 year. Includes outreach programs.
  - Christmas at the Inn, December 1993; Invitations, drafts, programs (Box 34, Folder 2)
    related to Women's Committee presentation of a benefit for Ojai Festivals Community Outreach and Education
  - City of Ojai 1992, Contracts, correspondence, drafts (Box 39, Folder 10)
    Related to necessary permits and contracts with the city of Ojai for the Festival.
  - City of Ojai Festival '93 Application, 1991-1993; Contracts, correspondence (Box 30, Folder 6)
    contracts with the City of Ojai for the 93 Festival
  - Compact discs Pre-order forms, 1994-1995; Papers and brochures (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Information regarding complimentary CDs for donors; planning and order forms for pre-ordering of '95 Festival tickets and souvenirs
  - Concert Repertoire Festival '95, 1995; Papers (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Drafts of Festival program for 1995 season.
  - Conductor's Circle at the home of Ray & Yvette Ellis, March 1995; invitations, drafts, correspondence (Box 32, Folder 6)
    Conductor's Circle event planning for private program in Ojai
  - Contracts Festival '91, 1991; Contracts, correspondence, drafts (Box 39, Folder 11)
    Contracts for 1991 Festival, including performers and engineers.
  - Corporate Brochure, 1992; papers (Box 59, Folder 4)
    Drafts of Ojai brochure.
  - Debriefing Festival '93, 1993; Spreasheets, memos (Box 30, Folder 12)
    Wrap-up materials following 93 Festival, including ideas for 94 Festival
  - Diamond Litho, 1992; papers (Box 44, Folder 5)
    Statements/bills, drafts of changes to the program.
  - Donations/Support from festivals to other organizations/events, 1992-1993; papers and program (Box 51, Folder 7)
    Related to donation made by Ojai Festivals to the 1992 Festival of Trees
  - Doubletree Hotel, 1992; bills and faxes (Box 39, Folder 6)
    related to room charges at Doubletree Hotel in Pasadena. Billed to Joan Kemper of the Ojai Festival
  - Educational Concert Series Ventura Symphony and Ojai Festivals, 1993; papers (Box 53, Folder 7)
    Correspondence regarding the Educational Concert Series.
  - Family Concert Festival '95, 1993-1995; Brochures, drafts, contracts (Box 34, Folder 1)
    Related to family programming at Ojai
  - Festival '92 in review and debriefing, 1992; drafts and correspondence (Box 38, Folder 2)
    commentary of 1992 Festivals with ideas for future years
  - Festival '92 Parking, 1992; parking passes and records (Box 38, Folder 1)
    information regarding parking for the 1992 Ojai Festival
  - Festival 93 Program Draft, 1993; photocopies and originals (Box 29, Folder 4)
    Draft of full program for 1993 Festival, with corrections
  - Festival 93 Scholarship Winners, 1993; Copies of letters (Box 30, Folder 14)
    letters to scholarship recipients
  - Festival '93 Travel, 1993; Itineraries and correspondence (Box 29, Folder 3)
    Materials related to the travel of Festival artists
  - Festivals 1996, papers, clippings, programs (Box 25, Folder 3)
    materials related to 1996 Festival including Women's Committee papers
  - Festivals 97, 1997; programs; pamphlet (Box 25, Folder 4)
    2 programs and order form for Festival '97, featuring Emmanuel Ax
  - Finance: OFCOE '93 Saddle Songs, 1993; faxes and pamphlet (Box 27, Folder 1)
    Materials related to the Ojai Festivals Community Outreach and Education "Saddle Sings" program
  - Financial Reports, 1986-1988; papers (Box 83, Folder 1)
    Financial records kept by the Ojai Women's Committee.
  - Frances Wyle, 1976; Correspondence and news clippings (Box 40, Folder 18)
    Related to gifts to the Festival made in honor of Frances Wyle, longtime resident of Ojai Valley.
  - French Consulate, 1994-1995; correspondence (Box 32, Folder 5)
    related to French programming
  - Gerhard Samuel and Stan Weinstein, 1970-1971; correspondence, news clippings, (Box 40, Folder 3)
    Related to Gerhard Samuel, who was music director of the Festival in 1970 and Stan Weinstein, who had been managing director.
    Samuel and Weinstein's contracts were not renewed.
  - Gerry Roe Pres. 1995-96, 1995-1996; Papers (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Board of directors minutes; memos; press clippings; correspondence
  - Gold Card Hospitality Suite 1993, correspondence and drafts (Box 30, Folder 15)
    Related to special service for high level donors of Festival.
  - Graphic ideas/Prices 1992, Brochures, correspondence (Box 43, Folder 7)
    Information from various graphic vendors for the 1992 Festival.
  - Hartford Foundation, 1950s?; Photographs and copies (Box 65, Folder 4)
    2 bound books of pictures of the Hartford Foundation; original photographs
  - Hotel reservation-Press, 1992; Bills, correspondence (Box 39, Folder 20)
    Hotel arrangements at the Ojai Rancho Motel for members of the press.
  - Housing, 1984-1991; papers (Box 74, Folder 3)
    Correspondence and plans for housing of various Festival musicians, such as members of the Scottish Chamber Orchestra.
  - Housing for Artists 1992, correspondence, contracts, drafts (Box 38, Folder 4)
    Related to housing of artists, both in private homes and hotels
  - Housing-Artists Festival '93, 1993; Contracts, correspondence (Box 30, Folder 7)
    Relevant to housing of Festival artists in local Ojai homes
  - Huntington Hartford archive correspondence, 1965-1978; papers (Box 65, Folder 2)
    Correspondence between archivists, lawyers and members of Hartford's estate
  - Insurance 1995/96 Property: American States Liability: CNA, papers, brochures (Box 75, Folder 3)
    Correspondence and statements regarding insurance policies held by the Festival.
  - John Cage Estate -- 1993 Festival, correspondence (Box 31, Folder 3)
    Related to possibility of dedicating concerts to John Cage
  - K. Hubbard Design, 1992; papers (Box 44, Folder 4)
    Correspondence, drafts, final program with work by K. Hubbard Design.
  - K. Hubbard Design Contract/Dispute, 1992; papers, brochures (Box 44, Folder 3)
    Related to designs used in the program, contracts, correspondence.
  - L. Morton Memorial, 1980's-1990's; programs, correspondence, news clippings (Box 38, Folder 9)
    Related to death of Lawrence Morton and the commemorative programming done at the festival in his honor.
  - Larry Hagman Benefit, April 30, 1995; Invitations, contracts, correspondence, drafts (Box 33, Folder 5)
    Related to benefit held at Mr. and Mrs. Larry Hagman's residence.
  - Lawrence Morton, 1960s-1980s; Correspondence, news clippings, copies of photographs (Box 38, Folder 8)
    Related to former director of Ojai Festival, Lawrence Morton.
  - Lisa Gerardin Paper Moon Graphics, September 1992; papers, brochures (Box 59, Folder 3)
    Paper samples and correspondence from Paper Moon Graphics
  - Los Angeles Preview Festival '95 Peter Rawley's House May 13, May, 1995; invitations, drafts, correspondence (Box 32, Folder 9)
    Planning for preview event at private home
  - Mailing List/ Silent Auction, 1986-1987; papers (Box 83, Folder 3)
    Lists of addresses and contact info; planning information for silent auction.
  - Members and Volunteers, 1985-1988; papers (Box 84, Folder 5)
    Letters to potential volunteers and members; lists of members; recommendations for members and volunteers
    All pertaining to the Ojai Women's Committee
  - Minutes, 1985-1987; papers (Box 84, Folder 1)
    Official minutes of the Ojai Women's Committee.
  - Miscellaneous photographs, 1998-99?; photographs (Box 47, Folder 4)
    Photographs of flowers and people. One photograph is labeled 1998-99 Board. Others are blank.
  - Music Critics Letter Press Lists, 1995; Papers (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Press releases and lists for '95 season of the Festival.
  - Music Libraries, 1979-1991; papers (Box 74, Folder 2)
    Correspondence with music librarians; inventory of Ojai Festival's music holdings
  - National Society of Fundraising Executives (N.S.F.R.E.), 1993; pamphlet, memo (Box 34, Folder 3)
    Information about the Ojai Festival's lapsed membership in NSFRE
  - Newsletters, 1984-1990; papers (Box 84, Folder 3)
    Newsletters of the Ojai Women's Committee, for internal use within the Committee.
  - O & E 1992-93 Schedule and Information; Database, 1992-1993; papers (Box 61, Folder 10)
    Mailing lists and correspondence relating to Ojai Festivals Community Outreach & Education
  - OF 93-94 Calendar; Facilities: Oxnard Auditorium, 1993-1994; Contracts, correspondence (Box 32, Folder 4)
    Draft of calendar; drafts of contract with Oxnard Auditorium
  - OFCOE "Looking for a logo" April 1993 Entries, papers (Box 62, Folder 6)
    Entries/designs for an OFCOE logo.
  - OFCOE Letters from Children, 1993; papers (Box 62, Folder 4)
    Handwritten letters from children to the Ojai Festival regarding outreach/educational programming
  - Oglesby, Carla Artist, 1991; correspondence, brochures (Box 43, Folder 6)
    Information provided by graphic designer Carla Oglesby.
  - Ojai Day 1993 October 9, 1993, 1992-1993; papers (Box 53, Folder 6)
    Information about Ojai Day '93, a community festival.
  - Ojai Presbyterian Church, 1992; Correspondence (Box 38, Folder 3)
    Related to rental of church for Ojai Festival performances
  - Ojai Preview (Art Center) June 4th Festival '95, May, June 1995; invitations, drafts, correspondence (Box 32, Folder 10)
    Planning for preview event
  - Otis Chandler Event March 11 '95 Museum of Transportation, Oxnard, 1995; Invitations, receipts, correspondence (Box 33, Folder 3)
    Related to benefit concert hosted by Mr. and Mrs. Otis Chandler
  - Patrons' Concert 11/3/94, 11/94; invitations, drafts, correspondence (Box 32, Folder 7)
    Relevant to program organized by Women's Committee for donors
  - Peter Rawley--Bach, Bernstein, and Blues, 1994; papers (Box 32, Folder 2)
    Mailing list for BB&B program; artist information about Peter Rawley
  - Porta Potties 1992, Contracts and proposals (Box 39, Folder 7)
    Information from different vendors, such as JW Enterprises and BFI Services Group.
  - Posters--Festival '93, 1993; correspondence and drafts (Box 30, Folder 4)
    Related to distribution of posters for 1993 Festival
  - Potential suppliers for Production, 1992; brochures, correspondence (Box 39, Folder 18)
    Related to production suppliers, such as Entertainment Lighting Service and The Tamis Corporation.
  - PR Newswire 1987-88, 1987-1988; brochures, correspondence (Box 41, Folder 5)
    Information about PR Newswire as potential vendor.
  - President's Party Festival '93, 1993; papers (Box 53, Folder 11)
    Mailing and attendance lists
  - Printing and printing companies, 1991-1993; brochures (Box 59, Folder 1)
    Samples and brochures from printing companies
  - Printing: programs and posters, 1992; papers, brochures (Box 87, Folder 1)
    Invoices, sketches and drafts of programs. Includes end product of the 1992 program.
  - Production '93 Sound, Lighting, 1992; Letter (Box 30, Folder 10)
    Letter from potential sound/lighting vendor
  - Production '93 Ticket graphics--Various, 1993; ticket drafts (Box 29, Folder 2)
    Drafts of tickets for the 93 Festival, including gift subscriptions for tickets
  - Production Schedule 1993, schedule drafts (Box 30, Folder 4)
    Internal drafts of production schedule for 1993 Festival
  - Production vendors contracts '91, '92, 1991-1992; Contracts, correspondence, drafts (Box 39, Folder 5)
    Related to vendors of the 1991 and 1992 Festivals, including the Ojai Presbyterian Church and Pascone Piano Service.
  - Production-General, 1990-1991; papers (Box 74, Folder 4)
    Correspondence and planning for production of the Festival, including staff lists and contracts with the City of Ojai.
  - Publishers, 1990-1992; newsletters and correspondence (Box 41, Folder 9)
    Information from music publishers (eg Boosey & Hawkes, Oxford University Press) about new and upcoming publications
  - Rehearsal Schedules Festival '93, 1993; schedule drafts (Box 31, Folder 8)
    Rehearsal space bookings for artists and groups
  - Roger Kellaway/Dick Stoltzman Benefit at Thousand Oaks Civic Plaza, 1995; brochures, correspondence, press releases (Box 33, Folder 4)
    Related to Bach, Bernstein & Blues, a benefit concert held on March 16, 1995 in Thousand Oaks.
  - Royalties/Broadcast Obligations, 1991; papers, programs (Box 72, Folder 3)
    Correspondence and contracts with NPR affiliates for broadcasts of Ojai performances